<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Articles made and published by the king of France, touching the re-establishment and re-appeale of the Iesuits to their liberties in France with a sentence or decree made and published against them, by the court of Parliament in Paris, the 23. day of December last past, 1611.</title>
            <author>France. Sovereign (1589-1610 : Henry IV)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1612</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 14 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 8 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A06361</idno>
            <idno type="STC">STC 16829.5</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC S92933</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">34382486</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 34382486</idno>
            <idno type="VID">28990</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A06361)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 28990)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1475-1640 ; 1901:2)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Articles made and published by the king of France, touching the re-establishment and re-appeale of the Iesuits to their liberties in France with a sentence or decree made and published against them, by the court of Parliament in Paris, the 23. day of December last past, 1611.</title>
                  <author>France. Sovereign (1589-1610 : Henry IV)</author>
                  <author>Louis XIII, King of France, 1601-1643.</author>
                  <author>Henry IV, King of France, 1553-1610.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 11 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Thomas Archer, and are to be sold in Popes-head Palace,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1612.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>STC (2nd ed.) attributes this work to Louis XIII, but text of the item states it to be a proclamation of Henry IV, first published in 1603.</note>
                  <note>Error in paging: p.3 numbered 5.</note>
                  <note>Signatures: A-B⁴.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Jesuits.</term>
               <term>France --  Church history --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-09</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-11</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:28990:1"/>
            <p>ARTICLES made and publiſhed by the King of <hi>France,</hi> touching the re-eſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment and re-appeale of the <hi>Ieſuits</hi> to their Liberties in <hi>France.</hi> With A Sentence or Decree made and publiſhed againſt them, by the Court of Parliament in <hi>Paris,</hi> the 23. day of December laſt paſt, 1611.</p>
            <figure>
               <figDesc>printer's or publisher's device</figDesc>
            </figure>
            <p>LONDON Printed for <hi>Thomas Archer,</hi> and are to be ſold in Popes-head Palace. 1612.</p>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="royal_articles_concerning_the_Jesuits">
            <pb facs="tcp:28990:2"/>
            <pb n="1" facs="tcp:28990:2"/>
            <head>ARTICLES made and publi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſhed by the King of <hi>France, touching the re-eſtabliſhment and</hi> re-appeale of the Ieſuits to their liber<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties in <hi>France:</hi> With a Sentence or De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cree made and publiſhed againſt them, by the Court of Parliament in <hi>Paris,</hi> the 23. day of December laſt paſt. 1611.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>ENRIE, by the grace of God King of France and Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uarre:</signed> 
               <salute>To al men to whom theſe preſents ſhall come greeting.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Theſe are to let you and euery one of you, to know and vnderſtand, that deſiring to hearken vnto and to grant the requeſt made vnto vs, by our Holie Father the
<pb n="2" facs="tcp:28990:3"/> Pope, concerning the reeſtabliſhment of the Ieſuits in this our Realm of France, and for certaine good and great conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>rations vs thereunto mouing. We haue cauſed theſe our letters pattents to bee made, ſigned with our owne hand, and of our ſpeciall grace, full power and au<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thority Royall, doe giue and grant vnto all the ſocietie and companie of Ieſuites free liberty and power to dwell and re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſide in ſuch places where at this preſent they finde them ſelues to bee eſtabliſhed within this our Realme of France, that is in the Townes of Tholoze, Agen, Rhode, Londem, Perigeux, Linoges, Tournon, Le pois, Aulenat, Beziers and beſides theſe places at the requeſt of his ſaid holineſſe and in regard of the ſin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gular affection which we beare vnto him, wee haue further granted, and permit them to place and reeſtabliſh themſelues in our Townes of <hi>Lyon, Dijon,</hi> and parti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cularly in our houſe of <hi>La Fleſche</hi> in <hi>An<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iou?</hi> There to continew and eſtabliſhe their reſidence, neuertheleſſe vpon theſe conditions and prohibitions following.</p>
            <list>
               <item>1 Firſt, that they ſhal not erect any Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>leges nor places of Reſidence in anie Towne or place of this our Realme, Countries, or Lands, and Seigniorie,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:28990:3"/> vnder our obedience, vnleſſe it bee by our expreſſe licence and permiſſion, vpn paine to forfet and loſe the benefit of theſe their letters pattents of the ſaid reeſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment.</item>
               <item>2 That all thoſe that are of the ſaid Societie within our ſaid Realme, as alſo their Rectors, and Prouiſors, ſhall bee naturall French men borne, and that no ſtranger ſhall bee admitted to be amongſt them, or to haue any place within their Colledges and Reſidencies, without our ſaid licence and permiſſion. And if there be any ſuch at this preſent amongſt them, they ſhalbe bound within three monthes after the publication of theſe preſents, to withdraw themſelues into their own Countries. Neuertheleſſe we doe by theſe preſents let you know, that wee in this word Stranger, comprehend not the Inhabitants of the Towne and Countie of <hi>Auignon.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>3 That the ſaid ſocietie of Ieſuites ſhall ordinarily haue one of their ſaid fellowſhippe, ſufficientlie authorized by them, to be our Preacher and to make ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>count vnto vs of the proceedings of their ſaid Societie, vpon occaſions miniſtred touching them.</item>
               <item>4 That all thoſe that at this preſent
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:28990:4"/> are within this our Realm, and that here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhall be admitted and receiued into the ſaid Societie, ſhall take their oathes before our officers of the places where they are reſident, nor to vndertake, nor doe any thing, contrary to our obedience, nor the publike peace and tranquillitie of this our Realme, without any excepti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on or reſeruation whatſoeuer. And that our ſaid Officers, ſhal ſed the acts &amp; pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ceſſe of their ſaid oathes worde for worde vnto our right deare and truſtie Chancel<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lor. And if any of them, that are now at this preſent admitted, or thoſe that here<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>after ſhall be permitted, doe, or ſhall re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſe to take the ſaid oath, they ſhall be for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ced, and preſently conſtrained to goe out of this our Realme of <hi>France.</hi>
               </item>
               <item>5 That from henceforth, all thoſe of the ſaid Societie, as well they that haue made ſimple vowes only, as the reſt of them neither ſhall, nor may not get, nor procure vnto themſelues within this our Realme of <hi>France,</hi> any moueable goods, and chattels, either by buying, gift, or o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>therwiſe, without our ſpeciall licence and permiſſion.</item>
               <item>6 They ſhall not take nor receiue a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny ſucceſſion, either direct, or collaterall, no more then other religious perſons,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:28990:4"/> neuertheleſſe if it fall out hereafter, that they are licenced by the ſaide companie, they may receiue into their Rites, as be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore.</item>
               <item>7 They ſhall neither take nor receiue any vnmoueable goods or lands, of thoſe that from henceforth ſhal enter into their Societies, but they ſhall be reſerued vn<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to their heires, or to thoſe to whom they ſhall haue diſpoſed the ſame, before their entrance into the ſaide Society.</item>
               <item>8 They ſhall alſo be ſubiect in all things, and in euery point vnto the lawes of our Realme, and puniſhable by our Of<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ficers, in ſuch maner, as all other eccleſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>aſticall and religious perſons are ſub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>iects vnto them.</item>
               <item>9 They ſhall not vndertake, nor doe any thing (either ſpirituall or temporall) to the preiudice of any Biſhops, Chap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters, Cures, and Vniuerſities, nor of any other religious perſons, but ſhall con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>forme them ſelues to the common Law.</item>
               <item>10 They ſhall not preach adminiſter the holy ſacraments, nor heare any mans confeſſion, but only of thoſe that are of their owne Society, if they be not per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mitted thereunto by the Biſhoppes of thoſe places, of the Courtes of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment where they are eſtabliſhed, that is at <hi>Bordeaux, and Diion,</hi> (Neuertheleſſe the
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:28990:5"/> ſaid permiſſion is not to be vnderſtood of the Parliament of <hi>Paris,</hi>) vnleſſe it be in the Towne of <hi>Lyon,</hi> and <hi>La Fleſche,</hi> wherein they are permitted to reſide and exerciſe their functions, as in the other places which are granted vnto them.</item>
               <item>11 And to the end that thoſe of the ſaid Society, which are at this preſent re-eſtabliſhed, may haue meanes to main<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>taine them ſelues and to liue in their Col<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ledges and reſidencies, we haue permit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted and by theſe preſents doe permitte them to enioy their rents and reuenues both preſent, and alſo that which hereto<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they haue had and enioyed, and if the ſame hath been ſeaſed vpon to our vſe, it is our will and pleaſure, that they ſhall be fully and freely reſtored vnto them a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gaine, without any let or interruption.</item>
            </list>
            <p>And to that end we will and com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mand all our welbeloued and faithfull Subiects, and ſeruants of our Court of Parliament, to allow of theſe our Let<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ters Pattents, and to cauſe them to be read, publiſhed, &amp; recorded, and that the ſaid company and Society of Ieſuites, may freely enioy and vſe their priuiled<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ges in the ſaid Letters Pattents, ſpecifi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed and ſet downe, and to cauſe al Roules &amp; Empeachments touching the ſame to
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:28990:5"/> end, &amp; to bee left off, for ſuch is our plea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure, and to the end that it may continew and remaine firme, and ſtable for euer, we haue hereunto put our ſeale, reſeruing vnto our ſelues, our owne right and pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>heminence as well in this as otherwiſe.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen at <hi>Roan,</hi> 
                  <date>in the moneth of <hi>Sep<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tember, Anno</hi> 1603. and in the 15 yeere of our Raigne.</date>
               </dateline> 
               <signed>Signed HENRIE:</signed> and vnderneath by the King ſealed with the great Seale in greene waxe and ſilke ſtrings.
</closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>Regiſtred. The Kings atturney general being here, after moſt humble decla<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ration made by him, vnto the ſaide Lords of the Parliament of <hi>Paris.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <dateline>
                     <date>The ſecond of <hi>Ianuarie.</hi>
                     </date>
                  </dateline> 
                  <signed>Signed Voiſin.</signed>
               </closer>
            </postscript>
         </div>
         <div type="Parliamentary_decree">
            <head>The Sentence or Decree made <hi>by the Court of Parliament of Paris,</hi> againſt The <hi>Ieſuites,</hi> vpon the 23. <hi>day of December laſt paſt.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>THe Court of Parliament, vpon the inrouling of the ſaid Letters Pat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, ordaine that their Counſell ſhall correct, and amend their Bils, and adde
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:28990:6"/> thereunto whatſoeuer they ſhall thinke conuenient within eight daies, and that they ſhall produce and giue contradicti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons and exceptions within the ſaid time preſcribed, and then to receiue ſentence.</p>
            <p>They further ordaine, that the prouin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciall and the reſt of his company deman<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dants in the caſe, and his aſſiſtants ſhall preſently ſubſcribe vnto the Submiſſion, made by their prouinciall, to conforme themſelues vnto the Doctryne of the <hi>Sor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>boniſts,</hi> ſpecially in that which concer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>neth the preſeruation of the Kings moſt ſacred perſon, the maintaining of their authority Royall, and the liberties of the Church of <hi>France,</hi> which hath alwaies and moſt anciently been obſerued, and kept within this Realme of <hi>France,</hi> that being ſeen and communicated vnto the Kings Attourny general and the Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſel on both ſides they may haue iuſtice as Law and reaſon requireth. In the mean time, they haue and do make defence and ſtraight prohibitions vnto the ſaid So<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ciety, not to innouate, do, or vndertake a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ny thing contrary or to the preiudice of their Letters Pattents of reeſtabliſhe<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, nor of the decree or ſentence of the verification of the ſame, as alſo not to meddle or take vpo<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g> them either by them
<pb n="9" facs="tcp:28990:6"/> ſelues or by any other perſons appoin<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ted by them, to teach children within the City of <hi>Paris,</hi> in any wiſe whatſoeuer, neither yet to exerciſe the function of Scholars, vpon paine of forfeiture of their Letters Pattents of reeſtabliſh<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, reſeruing coſt and charges. Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nounced the <hi>23 of December, 1611.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
         <div type="letters_of_commandment">
            <head>The King of France Letters of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mandement to the Court of Parliament, for the verification of the ſaid Letters Pa<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents, and Articles aforeſaid.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <seg rend="decorInit">H</seg>ENRIE, by the grace of God King of France: and Na<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>uarre.</signed> 
               <salute>To our welbeloued and faithfull Subiects, the Officers of our Court of Parliament of <hi>Paris,</hi> greeting.</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>About a month ſince, we gra<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>ted our Letters Pat<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tents in maner of an edict, for the reeſta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>bliſhme<g ref="char:cmbAbbrStroke">̄</g>t of the Ieſuites in certain places of this our Realme, with certain excepti<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ons &amp; conditions therein mentioned, for verification whereof, according to our good will and pleaſure, it is our will and deſire that you ſhall content your ſelues, with the demonſtrations and reaſons which we haue ſet downe, and conſide<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>red
<pb n="10" facs="tcp:28990:7"/> of, with the beſt aduice and counſell which may be giuen by ſuch perſons as are altogether led and prouoked there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>unto with a good and entire affection, beſides that for our owne parts we haue ſuch pregnant reaſons that moue vs thereunto, that they ought not in any wiſe to be debated. Wee ſee &amp; know bet<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter then any other, what courſe we are to hold, and ſeeing that it hath pleaſed God by his grace to giue vs the meanes, to preſerue this veſſell from the ſtormes and tempeſts paſt, we meane ſtill to guide the Ruther, that it may ſaile the happelyer by the aid and helpe of God. We haue not granted them this reeſtabliſhment but vpon very good and materiall conſi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>derations, from whence we cannot ſwarue, without a moſt notable inte<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>reſt and preiudice to the good of our e<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſtate: for this cauſe therefore we will, &amp; expreſly command and enioine you by theſe preſents, ſigned with our owne hand, that preſently and without delay, you ſhall ratefie and confirme thoſe our ſaid Letters Pattents of edict, accor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ding to the forme and tenure thereof, without any refuſale prolongation, mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>deration or difficultie whatſoeuer, or without attending or looking for any o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther
<pb n="11" facs="tcp:28990:7"/> or more expreſſe commandement therein, either by word of mouth, or wri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ting, then theſe preſents, which ſhal ſerue you for the firſt ſecond and finall Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>miſſion, which you may expect to haue from vs, without referring your ſelues vnto the reaſons which haue moued you, to make the ſaid declaration vnto vs, or which hereafter may moue you to doe the like, which we haue well conſidered, but notwithſtanding the ſaid declarati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>on, and without any reſpect thereof. It is our will and pleaſure, that you ſhall proceed to the ſaid verification, for ſuch is our pleaſure.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Giuen in <hi>Paris</hi> 
                  <date>
                     <hi>the 27 of December,</hi> in the 15 yere of our raigne,</date>
               </dateline> 
               <signed>ſigned <hi>HENRIE:</hi>
               </signed> and a little lower by the King, ſealed with the priuie Seale in yellow waxe, Regiſtred.
</closer>
            <postscript>
               <p>The Kings Atturney generall, being heere vpon moſt humble declaration, made vnto the ſaid Lords of the Court of Parliament in <hi>Paris the</hi> 2 <hi>of Ianuarie.</hi>
               </p>
               <closer>
                  <signed>Signed Voiſin.</signed>
               </closer>
            </postscript>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
            <pb facs="tcp:28990:8"/>
            <pb facs="tcp:28990:8"/>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
